Guide to the Bronislaw Malinowski Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1869-1939; Series I
  - Correspondence of Bronislaw Malinowski
    - Lilliput, 1938 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 362, Reel 3)
    - Lindbaek, Lise, [1936 June 2, 1938 February 7] (Box 5, Folder 363, Reel 3)
    - Lipschütz, A., 1937 August 5 (Box 5, Folder 364, Reel 3)
    - Lisowski, [W.], 1937 January 22 (Box 5, Folder 365, Reel 3)
    - Horace Liverwright, Publisher, 1929 July 15 (Box 5, Folder 366, Reel 3)
    - Llewellyn, Karl Nickerson, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 367, Reel 3)
    - Locher, G. W. [Rijkmuseum voor Volkekunde, Leiden], 1938 (Box 5, Folder 368, Reel 3)
    - Lodge, Olive, undated (Box 5, Folder 369, Reel 3)
    - Logacki, Krysztof
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 405 - 409
    - Logemoh, S. O., 1931 June 28 (Box 5, Folder 370, Reel 3)
    - Löhnberg, Gerhart, 1934 March 24, April 4 (Box 5, Folder 371, Reel 3)
    - The London Group on African Affairs, 1933 August 8, 1936 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 372, Reel 3)
    - The London Library, 1933 July 12 (Box 5, Folder 373, Reel 3)
    - London School of Economics
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 616
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 617
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 618
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 619
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 620
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 622
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 623
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 624
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 625
    - Longchampt, Dr., 1932 September 9, 14 (Box 5, Folder 374, Reel 3)
    - Longmans Green and Co., Ltd., 1936 April 23 (Box 5, Folder 375, Reel 3)
    - Loram, Charles T., 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 376, Reel 3)
    - Lorimer, Lt. Col. D. L. R., 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 377, Reel 3)
    - Low, Barbara, 1933, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 378, Reel 3)
    - Lowenfeld, Margaret F., 1934 (Box 5, Folder 379, Reel 3)
    - Lowie, Robert H., 1927-1935 (Box 5, Folder 380, Reel 3)
    - Lovat Dickson and Thompson Ltd., 1936 April 20 (Box 5, Folder 381, Reel 3)
    - Lozitehlezi, Mbabane, Swaziland; Paramount Chief, 1938 July 19 (Box 5, Folder 382, Reel 3)
    - Lubienski, Zbigniew, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 383, Reel 3)
    - Lublinski, Ida, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 384, Reel 3)
    - Lugard, Frederick D., 1928 November 14, 1933 January 11 (Box 5, Folder 385, Reel 3)
    - Lutawska, Kazimiera [fragment], n.y. July 12 (Box 5, Folder 386, Reel 3)
    - Lutostański, K., 1930 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 387, Reel 3)
    - Lutosławski, Tadeusz, 1931 July 15 (Box 5, Folder 388, Reel 3)
    - Lutosławski, W., 1930 November 12, 15 (Box 5, Folder 389, Reel 3)
    - McConnel, Ursula H., 1918 November 26, 1919 April 5 (Box 5, Folder 390, Reel 3)
    - MacCurdy, John T., 1929 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 391, Reel 3)
    - McFarland, A. Ross
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 227
    - McGeagh, W. R., 1932 August 5, 26 (Box 5, Folder 392, Reel 3)
    - Mackenzie, Dudley Shannon, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 393, Reel 3)
    - Mackiewicz, Antoni, 1931 February 28 (Box 5, Folder 394, Reel 3)
    - Macmillan and Company, George A. Macmillan, 1925 March 30 (Box 5, Folder 395, Reel 3)
    - Macmillan, W. M., 1933 May 15, 26 (Box 5, Folder 396, Reel 3)
    - Macpherson, W. D.
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 699
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 700
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 701
    - MacRobert, N. M., 1931 July 30 (Box 5, Folder 397, Reel 3)
    - Madge, Charles, 1938 July 27, September 6 (Box 5, Folder 398, Reel 3)
    - Mair, Lucy P., 1931-1937 (Box 5, Folder 399, Reel 3)
    - Mair, [?], 1932 September 8 (Box 5, Folder 400, Reel 3)
    - Majumdar, D. N.
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 316
    - Maliniak, _______ [re: Feliks Gross], 1938 June 6 (Box 5, Folder 401, Reel 3)
    - Malinowska, Elsie R., 1917-1921, undated (Box 34, Folder 402-404)
    - Malinowska, Józefa, 1906-1918, undated (Box 34, Folder 405-409)
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 712
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 713
    - Malinowski, Hetty [daughter] [fragment], undated (Box 5, Folder 410, Reel 3)
    - Malinowski, Józefa [daughter], n.y. April 7
    - Malinowski, Jan [distant relation] n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 411, Reel 3)
    - Mallet, Sir Bernard
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 662
    - The Manchester Guardian, 1932 April 7, 1933 January 10 (Box 5, Folder 412, Reel 3)
    - Mancini, H., 1927 August (Box 5, Folder 413, Reel 3)
    - Mandato, Mario de [includes letter of B. Malinowski to the elder Mandato], 1936 March 18, 1938 September 11 (Box 5, Folder 414, Reel 3)
    - Mandelbaum, Miss _____, 1933 May 8 (Box 5, Folder 415, Reel 3)
    - Mannheim, Karl, 1938 May 9, 27 (Box 5, Folder 416, Reel 3)
    - Marett, R. R., 1933 January 27, 31 (Box 6, Folder 417, Reel 4)
    - Margold, Charles W., 1935 February 7, March 8 (Box 6, Folder 418, Reel 4)
    - Marriage Hygiene, 1936 March 26 (Box 6, Folder 419, Reel 4)
    - Marwick, Brian, 1936 November 15 (Box 6, Folder 420, Reel 4)
    - Marwick, [S. G.?], 1934 December 7, 1936 May 5
    - Masson, Sir David Orme and Mary, [1918], 1933-1938 (Box 6, Folder 421, Reel 4)
    - Masson, Elsie R.
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 402 - 404
    - Malecki, Tadeusz, 1924 November 2 (Box 6, Folder 422, Reel 4)
    - Matthias, Claus, 1938 February 3 (Box 6, Folder 423, Reel 4)
    - Mattson, Margaret Waid, n.y. September 1 (Box 6, Folder 424, Reel 4)
    - Maurizio, A., 1928 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 425, Reel 4)
    - Mayer, Gustav, 1938 May 19 (Box 6, Folder 426, Reel 4)
    - Mayo, Elton and Dorothea, 1918-1936 (Box 6, Folder 427, Reel 4)
    - Meek, C. K., 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 428, Reel 4)
    - Mehta, S. M., 1933 January 23, February 2 (Box 6, Folder 429, Reel 4)
    - The Men of the Trees, 1930 October 8 (Box 6, Folder 430, Reel 4)
    - Mendelson, B., 1936 November 9 (Box 6, Folder 431, Reel 4)
    - Menon, V. K. Krishna
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 61
    - Mensch En Maatschappij, re: Steinmetz issue, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 432, Reel 4)
    - Meredith, H. O. [Hugh Owen], 1931 October 19, 24 (Box 6, Folder 433, Reel 4)
    - Mermel, Stanisław
    - Methuen and Company Ltd., Publishers, 1932 March 30, April 28 (Box 6, Folder 434, Reel 4)
    - Meyendorff, Baron Alexander, 1932, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 435, Reel 4)
    - Meyerowitz, H. V., 1936 April 3 (Box 6, Folder 436, Reel 4)
    - Miller, Douglas, n.y. December 6, undated (Box 6, Folder 437, Reel 4)
    - Mitchison, Naomi, 1932 June 24 (Box 6, Folder 438, Reel 4)
    - Mitra, Achyuta R., 1937 November 17
    - Mond, Robert, 1919 January 21, April 8 (Box 6, Folder 439, Reel 4)
    - Montagu, Ashley
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 26
    - Montefiore, L. G., 1936 June 11, 26 (Box 6, Folder 440, Reel 4)
    - Moore, Eldon
    - Moore, Underhill, 1931, 1935, undated (Box 6, Folder 441, Reel 4)
    - Morant, [G. M.?], 1938 May 23 (Box 6, Folder 442, Reel 4)
    - Moreton, Frank E., 1936 July 23 (Box 6, Folder 443, Reel 4)
    - Morey, Robert H., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 444, Reel 4)
    - Morgan, [The Rev. E. L.?], 1933 November 23 (Box 6, Folder 445, Reel 4)
    - Morgan-Brown, Winifred, n.y. June 21 (Box 6, Folder 446, Reel 4)
    - Morris, Charles W., 1935 August 27 (Box 6, Folder 447, Reel 4)
    - Morris, John, 1931 August 11 (Box 6, Folder 448, Reel 4)
    - William Morrow and Company, Publishers, 1935 April 25, May 20 (Box 6, Folder 449, Reel 4)
    - Mottram, J. H., 1934 January 31, February 7 (Box 6, Folder 450, Reel 4)
    - Mühlman, Wilhelm, Emil, 1938 October 26 (Box 6, Folder 451, Reel 4)
    - Muirhead, Mrs., 1934 March 12 (Box 6, Folder 452, Reel 4)
    - Mumford, W. Bryant, 1932-1934 (Box 6, Folder 453, Reel 4)
    - Murchison, Carl
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 317
    - Murray, Gilbert, 1931, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 454, Reel 4)
    - Murrow, Edward R.
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 125
    - Muzeum Etnograficzne W Krakowie, 1938 August 31 (Box 6, Folder 455, Reel 4)
    - Myers, C. S., 1933 February 13, 15 (Box 6, Folder 456, Reel 4)
    - Myres, John L., 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 457, Reel 4)
    - Mysłakowski, Zygmunt, 1938 April 2 (Box 6, Folder 458, Reel 4)
    - Nadel, S. F., 1936 April 20, 1938 October 14 (Box 6, Folder 459, Reel 4)
    - National Museum, Melbourne; James A. Kershaw, Curator, W. Baldwin Spencer, Director, 1917-1921, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 460, Reel 4)
    - National Research Council; Edward Sapir, 1935 October 11 (Box 6, Folder 461, Reel 4)
    - Nature, Macmillan and Company, 1922, 1924, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 462, Reel 4)
    - Nauki Polskiej, 1931 November 20 (Box 6, Folder 463, Reel 4)
    - Needham, Joseph, 1924 August 17, 1938 June 23 (Box 6, Folder 464, Reel 4)
    - Neill, A. S., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 465, Reel 4)
    - Neuman, Gerhardt, 1937 November 14 (Box 6, Folder 466, Reel 4)
    - The New Education Fellowship, 1933, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 467, Reel 4)
    - The New Republic; Bruce Bliven, Editor, 1936 November 25 (Box 6, Folder 468, Reel 4)
    - New York City Public School 110, 1933 January 19 (Box 6, Folder 469, Reel 4)
    - Newlands, Harry Scott, District Commissioner, Gold Coast, 1929, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 470, Reel 4)
    - Ngcobo, Selby, 1938 August 12, September 30 (Box 6, Folder 471, Reel 4)
    - Nieuwenhuis, A. W., 1930 July 16, 1931 April 13 (Box 6, Folder 472, Reel 4)
    - La Nouvelle Revue Française; Gaston Gallimard, 1935 October 15 (Box 6, Folder 473, Reel 4)
    - Les Nouvelles Littéraires, André Gillon, 1936 May 14 (Box 6, Folder 474, Reel 4)
    - Nusbaum[ówna], Halina, 1914-1915 (Box 6, Folder 475, Reel 4)
    - Oberg, Kalervo, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 476, Reel 4)
    - Obreski, Józef, 1932-1938 (Box 6, Folder 477, Reel 4)
    - O'Brien, Daniel P.
    - Oldham, J. H., 1930 December 24 (Box 6, Folder 478, Reel 4)
    - Olivier, Gouverneur-Général [Marcel?], 1938 November 20 (Box 6, Folder 479, Reel 4)
    - Orestano, Francesco, 1938 October 26 (Box 6, Folder 480, Reel 4)
    - Organon, 1938 March 30, June 21 (Box 6, Folder 481, Reel 4)
    - Ormsby, Mrs. [incomplete letter from B. Malinowski re: Miss Beck], 1925 February 28 (Box 6, Folder 482, Reel 4)
    - Osborne, E. Allen, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 483, Reel 4)
    - Oxford University Press, 1938 October 18 (Box 6, Folder 484, Reel 4)
    - Paget, Sir Richard, 1938 May 30 (Box 6, Folder 485, Reel 4)
    - Paige, Jean B., 1936 September 14 (Box 6, Folder 486, Reel 4)
    - Palmer, The Rt. Rev. Edwin James, Chairman of the Archbishop of Canterbury's Commission on the Prohibited Degrees [marriage prohibitions], 1938 July 4, undated (Box 6, Folder 487, Reel 4)
    - Palmer, Paul
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 13
    - Parke, N. Ross, 1937 March 4 (Box 6, Folder 488, Reel 4)
    - Parke, Davis and Company, 1916 December 11 (Box 6, Folder 489, Reel 4)
    - Parkhurst, Helen, 1936 September 14, November 8 (Box 6, Folder 490, Reel 4)
    - Parliament of Religions, Sri Ramakrishna Centenary, 1936 July 30 (Box 6, Folder 491, Reel 4)
    - Patton, Dorothy and Dewey, [1935] April 10 (Box 6, Folder 492, Reel 4)
    - Peabody Museum of Harvard University; C. Ashenden, Assistant Librarian, 1921 August 9, 1936 November 5 (Box 6, Folder 493, Reel 4)
    - Pearl, Raymond, 1935 May 13, June 6 (Box 6, Folder 494, Reel 4)
    - Pearson, E. S., 1936 May 20 (Box 6, Folder 495, Reel 4)
    - Peck, Marjorie, 1915 November 18 (Box 6, Folder 496, Reel 4)
    - Penman and Company, 1930 May 8 (Box 6, Folder 497, Reel 4)
    - Perry, Henry F. E., 1935 April 18 (Box 6, Folder 498, Reel 4)
    - Perry, W. J., [1921 August 6?], 1928 December 18 (Box 6, Folder 499, Reel 4)
    - Peters, John F., 1938 August 18 (Box 6, Folder 500, Reel 4)
    - J. Peyronnet et Compagnie, Editeurs, 1932 December 15 (Box 6, Folder 501, Reel 4)
    - Pieter, Jozef, 1935 November 25 (Box 6, Folder 502, Reel 4)
    - Pim, Sir Alan
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 548
    - Pitt, Ernest R., 1918 (Box 6, Folder 503, Reel 4)
    - Pitt-Rivers, George H. L. F., 1927, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 504, Reel 4)
    - The Polish Mission in London, 1930 December 18 (Box 6, Folder 505, Reel 4)
    - Polish Press Bureau; J. H. Harley, 1922 October 19 (Box 6, Folder 506, Reel 4)
    - Pollack, [J.?], 1938 September 6, undated (Box 6, Folder 507, Reel 4)
    - Polska Akademia Umiejętności [Polish Academy of Sciences], 1926 December 29, 1931 April 25, 1936 July 18 (Box 6, Folder 508, Reel 4)
    - Polski Komitet Szkolny w Londynie, 1938 March 31 (Box 6, Folder 509, Reel 4)
    - Popitz, Dr., 1930 August 18 (Box 7, Folder 510, Reel 4)
    - Powdermaker, Florence, 1933 January 27 (Box 7, Folder 511, Reel 4)
    - Powdermaker, Hortense, 1936-1938
    - Powilatis, Helen, 1937 February 28 (Box 7, Folder 512, Reel 4)
    - Powys Mathers, Mrs. William ["Rosky"], 1932, undated (Box 7, Folder 513, Reel 4)
    - Poznański, W. and K., 1936 December (Box 7, Folder 514, Reel 4)
    - Protaszewicz, Helena, 1936 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 515, Reel 4)
    - Wydawnctwo, Przeworskiego, J., 1938 July 14 (Box 7, Folder 516, Reel 4)
    - Psychololgical Institute, Athens, Greece, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 517, Reel 4)
    - Pugh, Wilfred G., 1937 July 18 (Box 7, Folder 518, Reel 4)
    - Punicki, ______, 1938 October 18, 20 (Box 7, Folder 519, Reel 4)
    - Pyke, Geoffrey, 1931 July 31 (Box 7, Folder 520, Reel 4)
    - Radcliffe-Brown, Alfred R., 1922-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 521, Reel 4)
    - Radziwillowa, Princess Eugenie, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 522, Reel 4)
    - Ratcliff, A. J. J., 1938 October 24, 26 (Box 7, Folder 523, Reel 4)
    - The Rationalist Press Association, 1932 July 2, 1933 December 8 (Box 7, Folder 524, Reel 4)
    - Raum, Otto F., 1938 (Box 7, Folder 525, Reel 4)
    - Read, Aldona S. [Mrs. Duncan Read], 1935 May 22, June 17 (Box 7, Folder 526, Reel 4)
    - Read, Margaret H., 1935-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 527, Reel 4)
    - The Realist; Gerald Heard, Literary Editor, 1929 June 28 (Box 7, Folder 528, Reel 4)
    - Redakcja Przegladu Socjologicznego [Review of Sociology], 1930 January 7 (Box 7, Folder 529, Reel 4)
    - Redakcja, Ruch Prawniczy i Socjologiczny, Uniwersytetu Poznanskiego, 1928-1930 (Box 7, Folder 530, Reel 4)
    - Reich, Wilhelm, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 531, Reel 4)
    - Reiss, Erna, 1938 April 29, June 17 (Box 7, Folder 532, Reel 4)
    - Reeves, W. T.
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 677
    - Rich, Raymond T., 1937 June 17 (Box 7, Folder 533, Reel 4)
    - Richards, Audrey I. [includes correspondence of Dr. Richards with others], 1930-1938 (Box 7, Folder 534, Reel 4)
    - [Richards?], Gwynedd, 1938 September 28 (Box 7, Folder 535, Reel 4)
    - Richardson, Ian B., 1935 January 5, undated (Box 7, Folder 536, Reel 4)
    - Rivet, M., 1936 July 20 (Box 7, Folder 537, Reel 4)
    - Rivet, Paul, 1936 March 20
    - Robeson, Essie, n.y. July 20 (Box 7, Folder 538, Reel 4)
    - Rockefeller, David, 1938 May 1 (Box 7, Folder 539, Reel 4)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation: John V. Van Sickle, Edmund E. Day, 1930-1936 (Box 7, Folder 540, Reel 4)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation: A. W. Fehling, Daniel P. O'Brien, M. D., 1933-1937 (Box 7, Folder 541, Reel 4)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation: Tracy B. Kitteredge, 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 542, Reel 4)
    - Rogers, C. F. G., 1938 August 7, 22 (Box 7, Folder 543, Reel 4)
    - Romer, Eugeniusz and Zofia, 1936 May 8, 1938 August 14 (Box 7, Folder 544, Reel 4)
    - Rose, Alfred, 1934 May 15 (Box 7, Folder 545, Reel 4)
    - Ross, Sir Edward Denison, 1933 February 14, 15 (Box 7, Folder 546, Reel 4)
    - George Routledge and Sons, 1922-1938 (Box 7, Folder 547, Reel 4)
    - Royal Anthropological Institute, 1918-1938 (Box 7, Folder 548, Reel 4)
    - Royal Institute of International Affairs, 1938 October 17, 20 (Box 7, Folder 549, Reel 4)
    - Royal Society of New Zealand, 1936 June 3, July 9 (Box 7, Folder 550, Reel 4)
    - Russell, Bertrand, 1928 November 8, 1930 November 15 (Box 7, Folder 551, Reel 4)
    - Russell, Dora, n.y. (Box 7, Folder 552, Reel 4)
    - Rüstow, Alexander, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 553, Reel 4)
    - Sait, Una Bernard, 1938 January 18 (Box 7, Folder 554, Reel 4)
    - Saltonstall, Leverett and Alice, 1936 November 8 (Box 7, Folder 555, Reel 4)
    - Sargent, Porter, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 556, Reel 4)
    - Saville, William J. V., 1926 April-October (Box 7, Folder 557, Reel 4)
    - Schmidt, Johann L.
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 668
    - Schmidt, P. Wilhelm, 1924 January 20, May 6 (Box 7, Folder 558, Reel 4)
    - Schoch, Dr. Magdalene, 1931 March 28 (Box 7, Folder 559, Reel 4)
    - Schumann, Eva and Wolfgang, 1936-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 560, Reel 4)
    - Scott, Emmett J., of Harvard; letter of introduction to S. W. Green written for Malinowski, 1926 May 27 (Box 7, Folder 561, Reel 4)
    - Scott, Herbert S., 1934 August 8, 1936 June 15 (Box 7, Folder 562, Reel 4)
    - Scott, R. F., Master of St. John's College, Cambridge, re: thesis of Gregory Bateson, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 563, Reel 4)
    - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1938 February 15 (Box 7, Folder 564, Reel 4)
    - Seligman, Charles G. and Brenda, 1915-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 565 - 566, Reel 4)
    - Selly Oak Colleges, 1934 March 12 (Box 7, Folder 567, Reel 4)
    - Sexton, Helen, 1931 March 22 (Box 7, Folder 568, Reel 4)
    - Shand, Alexander Faulkner, 1924 May 9 (Box 7, Folder 569, Reel 4)
    - The Siemens Engineering Society; S. J. Clothier, Hon. Sec., 1925 December 29 (Box 7, Folder 570, Reel 4)
    - Siepmann, C. A.
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 74
    - Siersted, Ellen, 1938 August 8 (Box 7, Folder 571, Reel 4)
    - Simon, Sir Ernest Darwin, 1937 March 12, 16 (Box 7, Folder 572, Reel 4)
    - Simons, Jack, [193?] March 4 (Box 7, Folder 573, Reel 4)
    - Singer, Isidor, 1936 September 14 (Box 7, Folder 574, Reel 4)
    - Skarzyńska, Wanda, 1928 April 27 (Box 7, Folder 575, Reel 4)
    - Skokowski, Z. [?], 1930 December 19 (Box 7, Folder 576, Reel 4)
    - Smets, Georges, 1936 June 23 (Box 7, Folder 577, Reel 4)
    - Smolenski, Jerzy, 1931 June 9 (Box 7, Folder 578, Reel 4)
    - Sorokin, Pitirim Alexandrovitch, 1936 November 8, 18 (Box 7, Folder 579, Reel 4)
    - Souttar, Catharine E. B., 1937 February 4 (Box 7, Folder 580, Reel 4)
    - The Spectator, 1931 February-June (Box 7, Folder 581, Reel 4)
    - Spencer, Herbert, trustees of the estate, 1931 September-October (Box 7, Folder 582, Reel 4)
    - Spencer, W. Baldwin
    - Sperber, Hans, 1924 August 14 (Box 7, Folder 583, Reel 4)
    - Spier, Leslie, 1935 October 29, December 15 (Box 7, Folder 584, Reel 4)
    - Stang, Fredrik and Nini, 1936, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 585, Reel 4)
    - Staszewska, Eleonora [aunt], 1914-1922 (Box 7, Folder 586, Reel 4)
    - Sterling, Jane, undated (Box 7, Folder 587, Reel 5)
    - Sterne, E. S., 1938 October 26 (Box 7, Folder 588, Reel 5)
    - Stiglitz, L., 1935 December 6, 1936 July 2 (Box 7, Folder 589, Reel 5)
    - Stirling, E. C. and Harriet A., 1915-1918, undated (Box 7, Folder 590, Reel 5)
    - StoÅ‚yhwo, Kazimierz, 1928, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 591, Reel 5)
    - Stoneman, Ethel, 1921 January 22 (Box 8, Folder 592, Reel 5)
    - Stopa, Roman, 1935 July 5 (Box 8, Folder 593, Reel 5)
    - Stopes, Marie C., 1933-1938 (Box 8, Folder 594, Reel 5)
    - Strauss, Moses
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 115
    - Strong, W. M., 1916 May 7, [1918] (Box 8, Folder 595, Reel 5)
    - Swiderska, Karolina Władysławowa, 1931 July 9 (Box 8, Folder 596, Reel 5)
    - Szpotański, Kazimierz, 1938 August 17 (Box 8, Folder 597, Reel 5)
    - Szymberska, Zofia, 1931-1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 598, Reel 5)
    - Szymberski, Tadeusz, 1931-1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 599, Reel 5)
    - Taylor, A., 1934-1937 (Box 8, Folder 600, Reel 5)
    - Taylor, Margaret R., 1938 June 28 (Box 8, Folder 601, Reel 5)
    - Teppemna, [P. G.?] Consulate-General for the Netherlands in Melbourne, 1918 November 7, December 30 (Box 8, Folder 602, Reel 5)
    - Thilenius, Georg, 1930 July 3 (Box 8, Folder 603, Reel 5)
    - F. A. Thompson, Ltd., 1935 May 13 (Box 8, Folder 604, Reel 5)
    - Thurnwald, Richard C., 1930 October 30, 1938 September-November (Box 8, Folder 605, Reel 5)
    - Tomanek, Ludwik, 1938 December 6 (Box 8, Folder 606, Reel 5)
    - Torday, Emil, 1928 March 28 (Box 8, Folder 607, Reel 5)
    - Tozzer, Alfred Marston, 1936 November 8 (Box 8, Folder 608, Reel 5)
    - Trevor, J. C., 1938 May 23 (Box 8, Folder 609, Reel 5)
    - Troczyński, Konstanty, 1936 August 29 (Box 8, Folder 610, Reel 5)
    - Tuting, Rev. William C., 1938 January 28 (Box 8, Folder 611, Reel 5)
    - Underwood and Underwood, 1935 March 22 (Box 8, Folder 612, Reel 5)
    - Universities Bureau of British Empire, W. B. Brander, Secretary, 1933 September-November (Box 8, Folder 613, Reel 5)
    - University of Chicago [re: Kalervo Oberg], 1936 May 19, July 8 (Box 8, Folder 614, Reel 5)
    - University of Durham, 1936 July 17 (Box 8, Folder 615, Reel 5)
    - University of London, correspondence re: registration of Bronislaw Malinowski, 1913-1914 (Box 8, Folder 616, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science; correspondence re: sponsoring of New Guinea research, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 617, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, William H. Beveridge, 1923-1932 (Box 8, Folder 618, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, A. M. Carr-Saunders, 1933, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 619, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, W. J. B. Crotch, 1938 September-October (Box 8, Folder 620, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, W. C. Dickinson, 1926, 1935 October-November (Box 8, Folder 621, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, J. Mair, 1922-1934 (Box 8, Folder 622, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, Allen Mawer, Provost, re: G. M. Morant, 1936 June (Box 8, Folder 623, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, accounting department, 1931-1933, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 624, Reel 5)
    - University of London, London School of Economics and Political Science, miscellaneous correspondence and notices, 1922-1938 (Box 8, Folder 625, Reel 5)
    - Uniwersytet Warszawski, Rektor, 1930 February 7 (Box 8, Folder 626, Reel 5)
    - Vallance and Vallance; G. I. D. Draper, 1938 July 4, October 4 (Box 8, Folder 627, Reel 5)
    - Van Sickle, John V.
    - Vaucher, Paul, 1936 March 30, June 28 (Box 8, Folder 628, Reel 5)
    - Vayana, [Nino?], 1936 September 4 (Box 8, Folder 629, Reel 5)
    - Venables, Dr. John F., 1932 June 24, July 3 (Box 8, Folder 630, Reel 5)
    - Vierkandt, Alfred, 1930 July 15 (Box 8, Folder 631, Reel 5)
    - The Viking Press; Benjamin C. Gruenberg, 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 632, Reel 5)
    - Wagner, Guenter, 1935 June 30, 1937 March 17 (Box 8, Folder 633, Reel 5)
    - Waligórski, Andrzej, 1937-1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 634, Reel 5)
    - Wallas, Graham, re: Audrey Richards, 1926 November 15 (Box 8, Folder 635, Reel 5)
    - A. P. Watt Literary Agency, 1931 July 20 (Box 8, Folder 636, Reel 5)
    - Wattal, P., 1932 June 9 (Box 8, Folder 637, Reel 5)
    - Webb, Mrs. Sidney, 1929 November 13 (Box 8, Folder 638, Reel 5)
    - Weiant, C. W., 1936 December 3, 15 (Box 8, Folder 639, Reel 5)